ecards.co.uk 2011-12-27

# eCards.co.uk - Privacy - Send FREE e-Cards here! Birthday, Christmas, Romance and many more...

The eCards.co.uk Privacy Policy 

This Privacy Policy is our way of telling you what information we collect, how we use it, who we will disclose it to and how you can access, change and remove your information. 

Below you’ll find an explanation of the reasons we request information from you, as well as some details about how we obtain and use that information. 

eCards Media Limited will be the data controller for the purposes of the Data Protection Act 1998 in relation to personal information relating to you or third parties that is provided by you. 

Terms of Use 

Our [Terms of Use](http://www.ecards.co.uk/termsAndConditions.php) set out some important terms that apply to your use of the eCards website at www.eCards.co.uk. 

Use of information and your consent 

We can only collect your information for lawful and stated purposes. We can only use your personal information for the purposes stated in this Privacy Policy. By providing us with your personal information, you consent to us processing this information in one or more of the ways described in this Privacy Policy. 

Where we collect your personal information:- 

ECards   
If you ask us to send an eCard (the "Services"), we need your name and email address and the name and email address of the person you are sending the eCard to. You must have the consent of the recipient to give us their name and email address and also any personal information you disclose in your message to them. Providing this information is optional, but we cannot send an eCard on your behalf without you providing us with this information. 

If you insert an image, including a photograph, into an eCard from a source other than the Website, you must have the consent of the person whose image it is and/or the owner of that image to use that image before it is inserted into an eCard and to allow us to store the image for use by you in future eCards from time to time. In the case of images of children who are not capable of giving consent, you should ensure that the relevant consent is obtained from the child's parent or guardian. 

By inserting an image into an eCard from a source other than the Website, you confirm that you have obtained the necessary consents referred to in the above paragraph. We do not accept any liability whatsoever for any image inserted by you into an eCard from a source other than the Website without the consent of the person, parent or guardian and/or owner (as the case may be). 

If you are a recipient of an eCard then before you can open your eCard we will ask you to agree to this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use, by doing this you consent to us collecting, using and storing your personal information (including any image of you) in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

Customer service   
In order for us to respond to your questions or concerns, we may need personal information like your name, address and email address. This information is used to answer your questions as completely and thoroughly as possible. 

Targeting Advertising   
We collect other pieces of information when you sign up to our “Premium User Service” such as car & home insurance renewal, home ownership, car type, number of children, income level, gender, age, Broadband Supplier, Mobile Phone supplier, Newspaper readership, Job type, Pets, Sports, Interests & TV provider. We use this information to target relevant adverts to you. 

Information that we collect automatically:- 

There are many kinds of cookies, but these are the ones you need to know about…   
As well as the personal information that you provide us with, we will also use information obtained about you automatically from cookies (files which are sent by us to your computer). The main reason we use cookies is to gather information on how you and other users use our Website and Services. 

For example, cookies will tell us whether you viewed the Website with sound or with text on your last visit and will allow us to count the number of unique and return users to the Website. 

We may access cookies stored on your computer when you visit our Website in future or when you open an email from us. We are able to do this by including web beacons (also known as clear GIFS or web bugs) in our emails. If you want to delete any cookies that are already on your computer, please refer to the instructions for your file management software to locate the file or directory that stores cookies. Our cookies will have the file name “__utmb.txt, __utmc.txt, __utmz.txt, vis.txt, PHPSESSID.txt, lang.txt, user_cookie.txt”. 

For more information about deleting and controlling cookies visit www.aboutcookies.org. Alternatively, please refer to your browser manufacturer's instructions by clicking "Help" in your browser menu. Please note that by deleting our cookies or disabling future cookies you may not be able to access certain areas or features of our Website or send an eCard. 

Our web beacons do not store additional information on your computer but, by communicating with our cookies on your computer, they can tell us when you have opened emails from us. If you object to web beacons, we recommend that you follow the instructions for deleting existing cookies and disabling future cookies. We will still know how many of our emails are opened and we will automatically receive your IP address, a unique identifier for your computer or other access device; but we will not identify you as an individual. 

Third party cookies   
Please be aware that when you leave the Website via a link to a third party website, that third party website may use cookies and you will need to refer to the third party's privacy or cookie policy. 

What we will do with your information:- 

Personal information, additional information and information collected via cookies   
We use the sender's name and email address and the recipient's name and email address to send an eCard on the sender's behalf. We also use the sender's and recipient's information to notify the sender that we have sent the sender's card and that the sender's card has been read. 

Both sender and recipient information will be held by us so that if either the sender or the recipient choose to send an eCard in the future then we can fill in some of your details automatically for you when you send an eCard and can allow the sender to reuse images provided by the sender in future eCards from time to time. 

Any additional information you choose to give us about services, interests or lifestyle and information gathered via cookies will be used to learn about our users and improve the Website and Service we provide and advertising we show you. 

Third party use of information   
We may pass the information you provide to us to third parties who may use this information to decide whether to advertise with us and/or ask us to contact you on their behalf and/or contact you directly with offers of products, services and information that may be of interest to you. The personal information you provide may also be used for the purposes of: identity verification, credit and risk management, revenue collection, database verification and enhancement. 

We contract with a third party to deliver emails to our database of users. The third party is an accredited delivery platform which has been white listed with all major ISPs. 

At times, some information may be transferred to other countries including countries outside of the EU but we will always ensure that the country your personal information is transferred to has adequate levels of protection for your rights and freedoms in relation to processing such personal data in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998. 

We may disclose your personal information in order to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation, such as a request by the police. We may also transfer your data in the event that our business (or part of it) is sold, and the purchaser needs the data to carry on providing services. 

Marketing   
We may use the information supplied by you to contact you for marketing purposes, which may include sending you messages via email You can decide to opt-out of these types of marketing messages at any time by [contacting admin at eCards.co.uk](http://www.ecards.co.uk/help.php?#contact) or using the unsubscribe link at the bottom of our emails. 

Storing your information and keeping it up to date:- 

Access to your information   
When you share your personal information with eCards, you will always have access to this information. You can update, change or remove any information at any time by calling, writing, faxing or emailing us using the contact details set out below. 

If you want to find out what information eCards holds about you, please write to or email us at the address given below. We may charge you a small fee for providing this information. 

Keeping it safe   
We are committed to providing appropriate security controls to protect your personal information against foreseeable hazards. Making sure that your information is secure is very important to eCards. 

Links to third party websites   
On the Website we provide links to other third party websites. These third party websites are not controlled or in any way linked to eCards and this Privacy Policy does not apply to third party websites. 

Want to change your details, here's how:-   
If you would like us to update your contact information, remove your name from our mailing list, or if you have any questions about eCard's Privacy Policy or your personal information, please don't hesitate to contact us. 

eCards Media Limited trading as eCards.co.uk   
Unit 6   
Alverdiscott Road   
Alverdiscott Industrial Park   
Bideford   
North Devon   
EX39 4LQ 

Telephone number: +44 (0) 1237 420156   
Fax number: +44 (0)1237 470525 Email: [contacting admin at eCards.co.uk](http://www.ecards.co.uk/help.php?#contact)

eCards Media Limited is a company incorporated in England and Wales with Company number: 5455777. 

We will respond to your questions or concerns as quickly as possible. 

General Information   
The Terms of Use, the Privacy Policy and the Website are governed by English Law and the English courts shall have non-exclusive jurisdiction over any dispute.
